Vikhyath Benegal

Analyst at KPMG Global Services (KGS)

Summary

Vikhyath Benegal is an Analyst in KPMG Global Services working in the Regulatory Research Team in Hong Kong, China and the US. I'm passionate about what I do, and use my skills to do it in the best possible way one can. Nothing is more fulfilling than being a part of a team with similar interests, and an organization that values its employees. I believe in getting the job done in the most effective and efficient manner. In simple it means "To do hard work where needed and smart work where necessary"

For more information, visit http://vikhyath-benegal.branded.me

Experience

Analyst, KPMG Global Services at KPMG

September 2015 - Present (1 year 7 months)

General Manager at Opencube Labs

October 2014 - June 2015 (9 months)

- Recruitment and training of interns and campus ambassadors
- Marketing, sponsorship and event management of Opencube Labs event's
- Management of business operations and activities
- Logistics and support

Project Trainee at Indian Institute of Science

February 2015 - May 2015 (4 months)

 Conducted final year project on 'The Influence of sliding speed on coefficient of friction in SAE5120 and EN31 Steels'

Organization Committee Member at AIESEC in Mainland of China

January 2015 - February 2015 (2 months)

- Helped promote cross-cultural communication and better cultural understanding
- Tutored students of various age groups in English in Sichuan Province, China
- Worked with a group of 8 foreign nationals on various non-profitable projects
- Helped guide foreigners and managed and organized relevant activities for non-profitable projects
- Organized and participated in human library, workshops, cultural events and other teaching activities

Intern at Federal-Mogul Holdings Corporation

January 2014 - February 2014 (2 months)

• In-plant training and survey of production technologies being used and of the variety of different products produced

Certifications

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

KPMG July 2014

CATIA V5-DESIGNER

EDS Technologies July 2013

AutoCAD

CADD CENTRE INDIA PVT. LTD. August 2012

Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing (GD&T) in Design through Manufacturing

Indian Machine Tools Manufacturers Association January 2014

German Language Course - Level A1

Inlingua March 2013

Project Management: The Basics for Success

Coursera April 2015

Communication in the 21st Century Workplace

Coursera April 2015

Finance for Non-Financial Professionals

Coursera April 2015

Work Smarter, Not Harder: Time Management for Personal & Professional Productivity.

Coursera April 2015

The Art of Negotiation

Coursera April 2015

How to Understand Stocks

Udemy License UC - ZV6QS2YN September 2015

Finance for Non Finance Executives - Crash Course

Udemy License UC - 6B3LIW36 September 2015

Volunteer Experience

Fund Raising and Event Management Team Member at U&I Charity

September 2014 - July 2015

- Managed and organized various events like Under the Stars, Latin Food Festival and The Great Indian Charity Raffle under the U&I initiative
- Fund raising and campaigning for TCS 10K Run and U&I Charity Raffle
- Worked with the U&I fund raising and event management team on various awareness and social media campaigns and events to help fund the U&I school's for underprivileged children and metal health facilities

CSR Committee Member at KPMG

December 2015 - Present

- Head the CSR initiatives for RAK in Bangalore
- Helped promote CSR events firm wide
- Spearheaded various CSR activities for RAK in Bangalore
- Organised, managed and conducted various RAK specific events
- CSR Single Point of Contact (SPOC) for RAK

International Services Director at Rotaract

August 2015 - July 2016

The International Services Director is responsible for enhancing its Rotarct club member's knowledge of international understanding, goodwill, and peace through the world fellowship of Rotaract. The International Services Director initiates international projects with Rotaract clubs in other countries, supports Rotaract International programs and develops relationships with various Rotaract clubs around the world. Some of my responsibilities include:

- Organizing or sponsoring events that promote international understanding and awareness of other cultures
- Assisting and supporting international service project teams
- Promoting events for club members to attend, including Rotary conferences overseas
- Maintaining the club's relationship with clubs overseas and liaising with overseas clubs
- Published the club bulletin 'Beyond'. The bulletin showcased a set of innovative, proactive and insightful projects from 12 Rotaract clubs across various countries around the world. The bulletin helped raise awareness and promote better understanding about social and environmental issues being tackled in different countries

Rotaract Team Member at Rotaract

August 2014 - Present

- Involved in various community services projects tackling social, economic and environmental issues
- Education of underprivileged children at So Care Foundation
- Organized and managed social and environmental projects under the Rotaract Initiative

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency)
German (Limited working proficiency)
Konkani (Native or bilingual proficiency)
Kannada (Native or bilingual proficiency)
Hindi (Native or bilingual proficiency)
Chinese (Elementary proficiency)

Page3

Skills & Expertise

Cross-cultural Communication Skills

Event Management

Presentation Skills

AutoCAD

CATIA

Marketing

CAD

Solidworks

Solid Edge

Microsoft Office

Mechanical Engineering

Six Sigma

Sponsorship

GD&T

Leadership

Training & Development

Recruiting

Project Management

Matlab

 \mathbf{C}

Management

C++

Research

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Word

Education

BMS Institute Of Technology Management

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Mechanical Engineering, 2011 - 2015

Activities and Societies: Member of American Society of Mechanical Engineers and Member of Society of Automotive Engineers

Sindhi High School, Hebbal

2009 - 2011

Activities and Societies: House Captain

Bishop Cotton Boys School

1996 - 2008

Projects

Influence of sliding speed on coefficient of friction in SAE5120 and EN31 Steels.

February 2015 to May 2015

Members: Vikhyath Benegal, Vikas SV, Vishnu Nair, Siddharth Kashyap

The aim of this project work is to investigate the effect of sliding speed on coefficient of friction (COF) in EN31 flat specimen and SAE5120 pin specimen. EN31 is an alloy steel widely used for components like taps, gauges, swaging dies, punches, ejector pins, ball and roller bearings. Whereas, SAE5120 steel is used to produce components like gear wheels, pinions, connecting rods, and other parts. One of the recent significant applications of the pair of EN31 and SAE5120 steels is in continuous variable transmissions (CVT) systems.

Courses

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Mechanical Engineering

BMS Institute Of Technology Management

Manufacturing Processes – I, II, III

Material Science and Metallurgy

Mechanical Measurement and Metrology

Mechanical Vibrations

Mechanics of Materials

Mechatronics and Microprocessors

Operations Research and Management

Rapid Prototyping

Statistical Quality Control

Turbo Machines

Energy Engineering

Engineering Economics

Experimental Stress Analysis

Finite Element Methods

Fluid Mechanics

Heat and Mass Transfer

Hydraulics and Pneumatics

Industrial Engineering

Automation in Manufacturing

Basic and Applied Thermodynamics

CAD / CAM

Computer Integrated Manufacturing

Control Engineering

Design of Machine Elements – I, II

Kinematics and Dynamics of Machines

Management and Entrepreneurship

Independent Coursework

German Language Course - Level A1

Honors and Awards

RAK Achievers Awards - Spot Award

KPMG

April 2016

Awarded the RAK Achievers Award for 2Q16 – the Spot Award is an immediate show of applause where you have been chosen to be rewarded on-the-spot in recognition of your special and effective contribution.

RAK Encore Awards - Above and Beyond Award

KPMG

June 2016

Awarded the RAK Encore Award for 2Q16 – the Above and Beyond Award is awarded to individuals who consistently demonstrate behavior which is over and above their defined roles within the organization.

RAK Encore Awards - Citizenship Award

KPMG

September 2016

Awarded the RAK Encore Award for 2Q16 – the Citizenship Award is awarded to recognize and reward individuals who have consistently:

- participated in the KPMG Citizenship initiatives and spent time with the beneficiaries of KPMG's CSR programmes
- gone the extra mile and helped the Citizenship team facilitate its activities and programmes
- taken the initiative to put in additional effort to interact with KPMG partner NGOs and schools

Vikhyath Benegal

Analyst at KPMG Global Services (KGS)



2 person has recommended Vikhyath

"I worked with Vikhyath in Shall We Talk project, a project that was held by AIESEC Southwestern University of Finance and Economics. During my four weeks working with him, one thing that really caught my eye is that he is really energetic and passionate. He showed his excitement by accomplishing the tasks to the best of his abilities. He learnt fast ,adapted quickly and showed huge interest in other cultures. Not only that, he was also able to bring himself casually and professionally, depending on the circumstances he was in. Vikhyath is also a "team player", and I believe that he'll remain productive when it comes to teamwork.He posses an excellent skill set which he is able to display in his own unique way."

— Randy Mulyanto, worked directly with Vikhyath at AIESEC in Mainland of China

"Vikhyath is an ever smiling, humble person who believes in a working team environment. He is a fast learner. He is very dedicated and has a very detailed approach to any activity he takes on. In my experience of working with him for a biology project on bacterial behaviour, I found him to be very reliable. He contributed by not just doing his portion of the work but also by keeping the entire team motivated during the whole duration of the time."

— **Dheeraj PV**, studied with Vikhyath at Sindhi High School, Hebbal

Contact Vikhyath on LinkedIn